<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!--
    description:
    
    "EDoc Documentation"
    
    copyright: "Copyright (c) 2003-2006, Julian Tschannen"
    license: "Eiffel Forum License v2 (see forum.txt)"
    date: "$Date$"
    revision: "$Revision$"
    -->

<chapter xmlns="http://www.gobosoft.com/eiffel/gobo/documentation" id="edoc/installation">
	<chapterinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2005</year>
			<holder>Julian Tschannen</holder>
		</copyright>
		<author>
			<firstname>Julian</firstname><surname>Tschannen</surname>
		</author>
		<email>juliant@student.ethz.ch</email>
		<date>30 Oktober 2005</date>
	</chapterinfo>
	
	<title>EDoc: Installation</title>
	
<section>
	<title>Dependencies</title>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<strong>GOBO</strong>:
				To run <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> a CVS version of <ulink url="http://www.gobosoft.com">GOBO</ulink> is required.
				This is necessary because the GOBO Eiffel parser API changed since the latest release and <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> uses the new API.
			</para>
			<para>
				The CVS version should be newer than September 2005. The latest version used in developement was from 11. Oktober 2005.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<strong>Eiffel</strong>:
				<emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> works with ISE's and SmartEiffel's compiler. The tested ISE version is <emphasis>5.6</emphasis>, the SmartEiffel version is <emphasis>2.2 beta</emphasis>. When SmartEiffel 2.2 is fully compatible with GOBO's CVS version, <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> should be compatible as well.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<strong>Platform</strong>:
				The developement platform was Linux. But since the only dependency is GOBO and all file manipulation is done through GOBO's file system operations, <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> should run on all platforms which support GOBO and the mentioned Eiffel compilers. In particular Windows was tested with the ISE 5.6 compiler.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
	</para>
	<para>
		
	</para>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Installation</title>
	<para>
		To install <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> switch to the base directory of <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> and run <emphasis>'geant compile'</emphasis>. This will generate the executable.
	</para>
	<para>
		If you want to launch <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> from another location than the installation directory you should set the environment variable
		<strong>EDOC</strong> to the installation directory. If you always launch <emphasis>EDoc</emphasis> from the
		installation directory this is not necessary.
	</para>
</section>

</chapter>
